I am a program manager and engineer with 10+ years of experience getting thing done on time with low drama.

I excel at crossing team boundaries, spotting "missing conversations," and surfacing clear steps for action. My recent areas of expertise include full-stack web development, AWS architecture, data analytics, distributed computing and storage. I have participated in all phases of designing, developing, testing and deploying large-scale enterprise apps through dozens of successful releases. My goal is to work with a team I love; develop products that excite me and have a positive impact; and learn continuously.

# **Professional Experience**

## productOps, Software Engineer & Team Lead, 2014 - 2019

- Lead development, test, and release efforts using Agile practices and daily scrum. Facilitated meetings at all levels, from database schema with engineers to product strategy with clients.
- Improved company culture and productivity Mentored new employees to accelerate ramp-up time.
  Facilitated engineering "book club" tackling software engineering topics one chapter-per-week.
  Developed & delivered new-hire trainings to cement the company's collaborative engineering culture.
- Built web apps and SaaS plugins with Angular front-end and Node.js Express back-end. Participated in code reviews.
- Learned whatever tools necessary from project to project to deliver quality software on time.
- Developed best practices for browser testing, integration testing, and git VCS merge process.

## MapR Technologies, Sr. Curriculum Developer & Team Lead, 2012 - 2014

- Grew Training team to six, managing on-boarding and ramp-up plans for new hires.
- Created curriculum for Apache HBase NoSQL database, including Java programming labs.
- Assisted in curriculum design and review for Java-based MapReduce programming course.
- Developed class lab environment in AWS to spin up/down 10-node Hadoop clusters on demand.
- Researched and wrote technical documentation for all aspects of MapR's Hadoop distribution.
- Wrote Confluence Wiki plug-ins to programmatically render docs pages.

#### Marichiba Consulting, Program Manager & Web Developer, 2008 - 2012

Managed projects and programs for clients lacking time, capacity, or know-how.

- MobileMakerz Prototyped mobile mini-apps for restaurants, implemented with jQuery Mobile.
  Interviewed customers to gather requirements, and generated sales and marketing material.
- Hunter Finnell Media Designed and developed website and WordPress blog, showcasing the company's services with rich embedded video. Wrote all web copy. Administered the website and YouTube channel.
- In3 Finance Designed and developed website. Turned around a complete website in under three weeks, focusing on polished, established image for a financial services company.

## **Education**

## MBA with focus on Environmental & Social Impact and Organizational Development

Presidio School of Management, San Francisco, CA

### **Bachelor of Computer Engineering and Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

University of Minnesota, Duluth – Graduated magna cum laude. Minor in Mathematics.